playdoughtoplato.com 2019-07-04

# Privacy Policy - Playdough To Plato

Playdough to Plato, LLC believes very strongly in keeping your personal information confidential. The following policy describes what information we collect and how it is used and shared.

Playdough to Plato, LLC (“Playdough to Plato“, “we“, “our“, or “us“) is committed to protecting your privacy. This Privacy Policy sets out how we collect, store, process, transfer, share and use data that identifies or is associated with you (“personal information“) and information regarding our use of cookies and similar technologies.

Playdough to Plato provides web-based instructions and printable downloads that allow customers to lead literacy, math, science and STEM activities via our websites (our “Websites“) located at playdoughtoplato.com and thestemlaboratory.com (the “Services“).

This Privacy Policy applies to our Websites and the Services.

Before accessing our Websites or using the Services, please ensure that you have read and understood our collection, storage, use and disclosure of your personal information as described in this Privacy Policy.

## **CONTACT DETAILS**

Our full details are-

Full name of legal entity: PLAYDOUGH TO PLATO, LLC

Email address: HELLO@PLAYDOUGHTOPLATO.COM

It is very important that the information we hold about you is accurate and up to date. Please let us know if at any time your personal information changes by emailing us at HELLO@PLAYDOUGHTOPLATO.COM

## INFORMATION COLLECTED

Playdough to Plato is the data controller of the personal information we hold about you.

We process personal information about individuals that are our direct customers and, where our customer is a business or similar entity, individuals that are our customer’s employees, agents and other representatives. These individuals about whom we collect personal information are referred to as “you” throughout this Privacy Policy.

We collect personal information about you when you voluntarily submit information directly to us when you access our Websites or use the Services. This can include information you provide to us when you register for an account, fill in a form, correspond with us via the Websites, phone, email or otherwise, subscribe to our mailing lists, newsletters or other forms of marketing communications, respond to surveys or use some other feature of the Services as available from time to time.

If you choose not to provide personal information, we may not be able to provide the Services to you or respond to your other requests.

## STORING AND TRANSFERRING YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION

Security. We implement appropriate technical and organisational measures to protect your personal information against accidental or unlawful destruction, loss, change or damage. All personal information we collect will be stored on secure servers. All electronic transaction entered into via our Website will be protected by SSL encryption technology. Where you register for an account on the Services, you are responsible for maintaining your account’s security as more specifically explained in our Terms of Service.

International Transfers of your Personal Information. The personal information we collect may be transferred to and stored in countries outside of the jurisdiction you are in where we and our third party service providers have operations. If you are located in the European Union (“EU“), your personal information will be processed outside of the EU including in the United States; these international transfers of your personal information are necessary for the performance of our agreement with you in order to provide the Services.

## FOR EU VISITORS

YOUR RIGHTS IN RESPECT OF YOUR PERSONAL DATA

This section applies if you are located in the EU.

In accordance with applicable privacy law, you have the following rights in respect of your personal information that we hold:

Right of access and portability. The right to obtain access to and to receive your personal information.

Right to rectification. The right to obtain rectification of your personal information without undue delay where that personal information is inaccurate or incomplete.

Right to erasure. The right to obtain the erasure of your personal information without undue delay in certain circumstances, such as where the personal information is no longer necessary in relation to the purposes for which it was collected or processed.

Right to restriction. The right to obtain the restriction of the processing undertaken by us on your personal information in certain circumstances, such as where the accuracy of the personal information is contested by you, for a period enabling us to verify the accuracy of that personal information.

Right to object. The right to object, on grounds relating to your particular situation, to the processing of your personal information, and to object to processing of your personal information for direct marketing purposes, to the extent it is related to such direct marketing.

If you wish to exercise one of these rights, please contact us using the contact details at the end of this Privacy Policy.

You also have the right to lodge a complaint to your local data protection authority. Further information about how to contact your local data protection authority is available at <http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/bodies/authorities/index_en.htm>.

## COOKIES / IP ADDRESS TRACKING

When you use our Service, read our emails, or otherwise engage with us through a computer or mobile device, we and our third party service providers, automatically collect information about how you access and use the Service and information about the device you use to access the Service. We use this information to enhance and personalize your user experience, to monitor and improve our websites and services, and for other internal purposes.

Our Websites use cookies to distinguish you from other users of our Websites. Cookies are pieces of code that allow for personalization of our Websites by saving your information such as user ID and other preferences. A cookie is a small data file that we transfer to your device’s hard disk (such as your computer or smartphone) for record-keeping purposes.

We may collect analytics data, or use third-party analytics tools such as Google Analytics, to help us measure traffic and usage trends for the Service and to understand more about the demographics of our users. You can learn more about Google’s practices at <https://policies.google.com/privacy/partners>, and view its currently available opt-out options at <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>.

We may also work with third party partners to employ technologies, including the application of statistical modelling tools, which permit us to recognize and contact you across multiple devices.

Although we do our best to honor the privacy preferences of our users, we are unable to respond to Do Not Track signals set by your browser at this time.

The cookies we use are designed to help you get the most from our Websites but if you do not wish to receive cookies, most browsers allow you to change your cookie settings. Please note that if you choose to refuse cookies you may not be able to use the full functionality of our Websites. These settings will typically be found in the “options” or “preferences” menu of your browser. In order to understand these settings, the following links may be helpful, otherwise you should use the “Help” option in your browser for more details.

[Cookie settings in Safari web](https://support.apple.com/kb/PH5042?locale=en_GB) and [iOS](https://support.apple.com/en-gb/HT201265)

Deleting cookies does not delete non-cookie technologies such as Local Storage Objects (LSOs) such as Flash objects and HTML5. You can learn more about Flash objects – including how to manage privacy and storage settings for Flash cookies – on Adobe’s website or by clicking [here](https://helpx.adobe.com/flash-player/kb/disable-local-shared-objects-flash.html). Various browsers may offer their own management tools for removing HTML5 LSOs.

## THIRD PARTY ADVERTISING

We allow third-party companies to serve ads and/or collect certain anonymous information when you visit our web site. These companies may use non-personally identifiable information (e.g., click stream information, browser type, time and date, subject of advertisements clicked or scrolled over) during your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services likely to be of greater interest to you. These companies typically use a cookie or third party web beacon to collect this information. To learn more about this behavioral advertising practice or to opt-out of this type of advertising, you can visit <http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices>, the DAA’s resources at [www.aboutads.info/choices](http://www.aboutads.info/choices) and/or Your Online Choices at [www.youronlinechoices.com/uk](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/uk).

Please note that opting-out of receiving interest-based advertising through the NAI’s and DAA’s or Your Online Choices online resources will only opt-out a user from receiving interest-based ads on that specific browser or device, but the user may still receive interest-based ads on his or her other devices. You must perform the opt-out on each browser or device you use.

Furthermore, some of these opt-outs may not be effective unless your browser is set to accept cookies. If you delete cookies, change your browser settings, switch browsers or computers, or use another operating system, you will need to opt-out again.

## LINKS TO THIRD PARTY SITES

Our Websites may, from time to time, contain links to and from third party websites. If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for their policies. Please check the individual policies before you submit any information to those websites.

## OPTING OUT

If Playdough to Plato chooses to send out email updates in the future and we have your email address on file, you may receive a copy of our newsletter.

However, at the bottom of every newsletter will be an easy way to opt-out. The editors of our site hate SPAM as much as you and have no intention of filling up e-mail boxes with unwanted messages.

## PERSONAL INFORMATION WE COLLECT WHEN YOU USE THE SERVICES

**CATEGORIES OF PERSONAL INFORMATION**

  * CONTACT INFORMATION AND BASIC PERSONAL DETAILS such as your full name, phone number, postal address, e-mail address, zip code. 
    * How we use it – We use this information to: 
      * communicate with you, including sending statements and invoices, communications, news, alerts and marketing communications;
      * deal with enquiries and complaints made by or about you relating to the Services;
      * authentication purposes;
      * create customer accounts and operate, maintain and provide to you the features and functionality of the Services.
    * Legal basis for the processing – The processing is necessary for: 
      * the performance of a contract and to take steps prior to entering into a contract;
      * our legitimate interests, namely administering the Services, for marketing purposes and communicating with users; and
      * to comply with certain legal obligations.

  * WEBSITE, BUSINESS AND MARKETING INFORMATION such as company website, IP address, current email list size, e-commerce software in use, email marketing software, product usage information, demographic data, data about customer’s 3rd party services, other business information (Facebook ad spend, status of business, industry, business goals). 
    * How we use it – We use this information to: 
      * operate, maintain and provide to you the features and functionality of the Services;
      * determine relevant advertising / marketing activities.
    * Legal basis for the processing – The processing is necessary for: 
      * the performance of a contract and to take steps prior to entering into a contract; and
      * our legitimate interests, namely administering the Services and for marketing purposes.

  * PAYMENT INFORMATION details such as your credit card information, account information, billing address and related information. 
    * How we use it – We use this information to facilitate payment for use of the Services and to detect and prevent fraud.
    * Legal basis for the processing – The processing is necessary for the performance of our contract with you and our legitimate interests, namely the detection and prevention of fraud.

  * CORRESPONDENCE AND COMMENTS when you contact us directly, e.g. by email, phone, mail, when you post on message boards, blogs or complete an online form or provide quality survey input, we will record your comments and opinions. 
    * How we use it – To address your questions, issues and concerns and improve the Services, to determine products and services that may be of interest to you and to send you news, alerts and marketing communications in accordance with your marketing preferences.
    * Legal basis for the processing – The processing is necessary for our legitimate interests, namely communicating with users and for marketing purposes.

  * ALL PERSONAL INFORMATION SET OUT ABOVE
    * How we use it – We will use all the personal information we collect to prevent and detect fraud, to operate, maintain and provide to you the features and functionality of the Services, to communicate with you, to monitor and improve the Services, our Website and business, and to help us develop new products and services.
    * Legal basis for the processing-The processing is necessary for our legitimate interest, namely to administer and improve the Services, our Websites, our business and develop new services.

  * CATEGORIES OF RECIPIENTS as required in accordance with how we use it, we will share your personal information with the following: 
    * SERVICE PROVIDERS AND ADVISORSThird party vendors ([Leadpages](https://www.leadpages.net/privacy), [HelloBar](https://www.hellobar.com/privacy-policy/), [ActiveCampaign email provider](https://www.activecampaign.com/privacy-policy/) and other service providers) that perform services for us, on our behalf, which may include providing mailing or email services, tax and accounting services, payments processing, data enhancement services, fraud prevention, web hosting, or providing analytic services.  **Your personal information is never transferred to any third-party for the purposes of re-marketing to you**.
    * PURCHASERS AND THIRD PARTIES IN CONNECTION WITH A BUSINESS TRANSACTION – Personal information may be disclosed to third parties in connection with a transaction, such as a merger, sale of assets or shares, reorganization, financing, change of control or acquisition of all or a portion of our business.
    * LAW ENFORCEMENT, REGULATORS AND OTHER PARTIES FOR LEGAL REASONS – Third parties as required by law or if we reasonably believe that such action is necessary to (a) comply with the law and the reasonable requests of law enforcement; (b) enforce our Terms of Service or to protect the security or integrity of our Services or Websites; and/or (c) exercise or protect the rights, property, or personal safety of Playdough to Plato, our customers or others.

  * RETENTION PERIOD 
    * For no longer than necessary for the purposes set out and in accordance with our legal obligations and legitimate business interests.

## ANNEX 2 – PERSONAL INFORMATION COLLECTED AUTOMATICALLY

  * CATEGORIES OF PERSONAL INFORMATION
    * INFORMATION ABOUT HOW YOU ACCESS AND USE THE SERVICES 
      * For example, the website from which you came and the website to which you are going when you leave our Websites, how frequently you access the Services, the time you access the Services and how long you use them for, whether you open emails or click the links contained in emails, whether you access the Services from multiple devices, and other actions you take on the Services.
      * How we use it – We use this information to: 
        * present the Services to you on your device;
        * determine news, alerts and other products and services that may be of interest to you for marketing purposes; and
        * monitor and improve the Services and our business, and to help us develop new products and services.
      * Legal basis for the processing – The processing is necessary for our legitimate interests, namely: 
        * to tailor the Services to the user and to improve the Services generally;
        * to monitor and resolve issues;
        * for marketing purposes;
        * to communicate with users;
        * to contact users;
        * and for the detection and prevention of fraud.
    * INFORMATION ABOUT YOUR DEVICE
      * We also collect information about the computer, tablet, smartphone or other electronic device you use to connect to the Services. This information can include details about the type of device, unique device identifying numbers, operating systems, browsers and applications connected to the Services through the device, information about the server upon which the Services operate, your Internet service provider or mobile network, your IP address.
      * How we use it – We use this information to: 
        * enable the Services to be presented to you on your device;
        * operate, maintain and provide to you the features and functionality of the Services;
        * monitor and improve the Services and business, and to help us develop new products and services.
      * Legal basis for the processing – The processing is necessary for our legitimate interests, namely: 
        * to tailor the Services to the user and to improve the Services generally;
        * to monitor and resolve issues;
        * for marketing purposes;
        * to communicate with users;
        * to contact users;
        * and for the detection and prevention of fraud.

  * CATEGORIES OF RECIPIENTS 
    * As required in accordance with how we use it, we will share your personal information with the following: 
      * SERVICE PROVIDERS AND ADVISORS 
        * Third party vendors and other service providers that perform services for us, on our behalf, which may include providing mailing or email services, tax and accounting services, payments processing, data enhancement services, fraud prevention, web hosting, or providing analytic services.  **Your personal information is never transferred to any third-party for the purposes of re-marketing to you**.
        * PURCHASERS AND THIRD PARTIES IN CONNECTION WITH A BUSINESS TRANSACTIONPersonal information may be disclosed to third parties in connection with a transaction, such as a merger, sale of assets or shares, reorganization, financing, change of control or acquisition of all or a portion of our business.
        * LAW ENFORCEMENT, REGULATORS AND OTHER PARTIES FOR LEGAL REASONSThird parties as required by law or if we reasonably believe that such action is necessary to (a) comply with the law and the reasonable requests of law enforcement; (b) enforce our Terms of Service or to protect the security or integrity of our Services or Websites; and/or (c) exercise or protect the rights, property, or personal safety of Playdough to Plato, our customers or others.

  * RETENTION PERIOD
    *       * For no longer than necessary for the purposes set out and in accordance with our legal obligations and legitimate business interests.

  * About
  * Latest Posts

### [Malia Hollowell](https://www.playdoughtoplato.com/)

Malia is a National Board Certified teacher who inspires educators with playful approaches to early childhood education. She earned her Master’s from Stanford University and has taught in Pre-Kindergarten through 2nd grade. Malia shares her motivating learning activities on her two popular teaching blogs Playdough to Plato and [The STEM Laboratory](http://www.thestemlaboratory.com/).

#### Latest posts by Malia Hollowell ([see all](https://www.playdoughtoplato.com/author/maliahollowell/))
